let set21=
[
    {
        question:`#1. The amount of heat required to change one form of matters to other without changing the temperature is called:`,
        options:
        [
'A. Latent heat',
'B. Fusion',
'C. Sublimation',
            'D. Evaporation',
        ],
        answer:`Answer: A`,
        exp:`Explanation: Latent heat, energy absorbed or released by a substance during a change in its physical state (phase) that occurs without changing its temperature. The latent heat associated with melting a solid or freezing a liquid is called the heat of fusion; that associated with vaporizing a liquid or a solid or condensing a vapour is called the heat of vaporization. The latent heat is normally expressed as the amount of heat (in units of joules or calories) per mole or unit mass of the substance undergoing a change of state. Latent heat arises from the work required to overcome the forces that hold together atoms or molecules in a material. The regular structure of a crystalline solid is maintained by forces of attraction among its individual atoms, which oscillate slightly about their average positions in the crystal lattice. As the temperature increases, these motions become increasingly violent until, at the melting point, the attractive forces are no longer sufficient to maintain the stability of the crystal lattice. However, additional heat (the latent heat of fusion) must be added (at constant, temperature) in order to accomplish the transition to the even more-disordered liquid state, in which the individual particles are no longer held in fixed lattice positions but are free to move about through the liquid. A liquid differs from a gas in that the forces of attraction between the particles are still sufficient to maintain a long-range order that endows the liquid with a degree of cohesion. As the temperature further increases, a second transition point (the boiling point) is reached where the long-range order becomes unstable relative to the largely independent motions of the particles in the much larger volume occupied by a vapour or gas. Once again, additional heat (the latent heat of vaporization) must be added to break the long-range order of the liquid and accomplish the transition to the largely disordered gaseous state.`
    },
    {
        question:`#2. The force of attraction between the molecules of water is called:`,
        options:
        [
'A. Adhesion',
'B. Cohesion',
'C. Attraction',
            'D. Absorption',
        ],
        answer:`Answer: B`,
        exp:`Explanation: Cohesion is the mutual attraction and sticking property of molecules. It is an intrinsic property in certain substances that is, commonly caused by the structure and shape of its molecules, resulting in electrical attraction. Cohesion paves the way for surface tension, establishing a solid-like condition where, in low density or light, materials can be set. Cohesion is also known as cohesive force or cohesive attraction. Cohesion promotes attraction between dissimilar molecules. This concept has many applications, the most common being its role in promoting coating strength. The strength in coatings refers to its cohesion measure to a substrate or surface. Without good cohesion, the coating is useless. As long as coatings remain sticking to the surface, the material is protected against: 1. Chemicals 2. Weather and environment 3. Impact 4. Stress and scratches`
    },
    {
        question:`#3. At what temperature water has highest density?`,
        options:
        [
'A. 0∘C',
'B. 4∘C',
'C. 10∘C',
            'D. 20∘C',
        ],
        answer:`Answer: B`,
        exp:`Explanation: When cooled from room temperature liquid water becomes increasingly dense, as with other substances, but at approximately 4 °C (39 °F), pure water reaches its maximum density. As it is cooled further, it expands to become less dense.`
    },
    {
        question:`#4. Which one of the following solid is compressible?`,
        options:
        [
'A. Wood',
'B. Stone',
'C. Gold',
            'D. Cotton',
        ],
        answer:`Answer: D`,
        exp:`Explanation: A substance in solid state has high intermolecular forces and hence has the least intermolecular spaces. So if compression is done here, then there is little or negligible amount of space for the molecules to come further closer. Hence, they are the least compressible.`
    },
    {
        question:`#5. Brass is a:`,
        options:
        [
'A. Compound',
'B. Element',
'C. Homogeneous mixture, ',
            'D. Heterogeneous mixture',
        ],
        answer:`Answer: C`,
        exp:`Explanation: Brass is an alloy made primarily of copper and zinc. The proportions of the copper and zinc are varied to yield many different kinds of brass. Basic modern brass is 67% copper and 33% zinc. However, the amount of copper may range from 55% to 95% by weight, with the amount of zinc varying from 5% to 40%.2 Lead is commonly added to brass at a concentration of around 2%. The lead addition improves the machinability of brass. However, significant lead leaching often occurs, even in brass that contains a relatively low overall concentration of lead. Uses of brass include musical instruments, firearm cartridge casing, radiators, architectural trim, pipes and tubing, screws, and decorative items. Brass Properties: 1. Brass often has a bright gold appearance, however, it can also be reddish-gold or silvery-white. A higher percentage of copper yields a rosy tone, while more zinc makes the alloy appear silver. 2. Brass has higher malleability than either bronze or zinc. 3. Brass has desirable acoustic properties appropriate for use in musical instruments. 4. The metal exhibits low friction.,  5. Brass is a soft metal that may be used in cases when a low chance of sparking is necessary. 6. The alloy has a relatively low melting point. 7. It's a good conductor of heat. 8. Brass resists corrosion, including galvanic corrosion from saltwater. 9. Brass is easy to cast. 10. Brass is not ferromagnetic. Among other things, this makes it easier to separate from other metals for recycling.`
    },
    {
        question:`#6. Thermometer is an instrument that measures`,
        options:
        [
'A. Temperature of substance',
'B. Heat of substance',
'C. Radiation of substance',
            'D. Flow energy in a substance.',
        ],
        answer:`Answer: A`,
        exp:`Explanation: A thermometer is an instrument that measures temperature. It can measure the temperature of a solid such as food, a liquid such as water, or a gas such as air. The three most common units of measurement for temperature are Celsius, Fahrenheit, and kelvin. The Celsius scale is part of the metric system.`
    },
    {
        question:`#7. Barometer measures:`,
        options:
        [
'A. Pressure',
'B. Atmospheric pressure',
'C. Wind velocity',
            'D. Gaseous pressure.',
        ],
        answer:`Answer: B`,
        exp:`Explanation: Barometer, device used to measure atmospheric pressure. Because atmospheric pressure changes with distance above or below sea level, a barometer can also be used to measure altitude. There are two main types of barometers: mercury and aneroid. In the mercury barometer, atmospheric pressure balances a column of mercury, the height of which can be precisely measured. To increase their accuracy, mercury barometers are often corrected for ambient temperature and the local value of gravity. Common pressure units include pounds per square inch; dynes per square centimetre; newtons per square metre (the SI unit called the pascal); inches, centimetres, or millimetres of mercury; and millibars (1 millibar equals 1,000 dynes per square centimetre, 100 pascals, or 0.75 millimetre of mercury). A barometer that mechanically records changes in barometric pressure over time is called a barograph. Though mercury,  barographs have been made, aneroid barographs are much more common. The motion of the aneroid capsule is magnified through levers to drive a recording pen. The pen traces a line on a graph that is usually wrapped around a cylinder driven by a clockwork mechanism.`
    },
    {
        question:`#8. People normally put some Naphthalene ball in the box in which they keeps cloths and winter blankets. After some weeks they find that there is no Naphthalene ball left in the box. Why does the Naphthalene ball disappears with time, without leaving any residue?`,
        options:
        [
'A. Condensation',
'B. Sublimation',
'C. Evaporation',
            'D. Diffusion',
        ],
        answer:`Answer: B`,
        exp:`Explaantion: Sublimation is the transition from the solid phase to the gas phase without passing through an intermediate liquid phase. This endothermic phase transition occurs at temperatures and pressures below the triple point. The term "sublimation" only applies to physical changes of state and not to the transformation of a solid into a gas during a chemical reaction. For example, when candle wax undergoes combustion, the,  paraffin is vaporized and reacts with oxygen to produce carbon dioxide and water. This is not sublimation. The opposite process of sublimation—where a gas undergoes a phase change into solid form—is called deposition or desublimation. Sublimation Examples: 1. Dry ice is solid carbon dioxide. At room temperature and pressure, it sublimates into carbon dioxide vapor. 2. Freezer burn results from the sublimation of ice into water vapor. 3. At the right temperature, the elements iodine and arsenic will sublimate from solid form into gaseous form. 4. Naphthalene, a chemical commonly used in mothballs, readily sublimates at room temperature and pressure. 5. Water ice will sublimate, although more slowly than dry ice. The effect can be seen over snowfields when the sun is out but the temperature is cold.`
    },
    {
        question:`#9. If we burn graphite:`,
        options:
        [
'A. Residue will be left',
'B. No residue will be left',
'C. It will not burn',
            'D. It will change into diamond.',
        ],
        answer:`Answer: B`,
        exp:`Explanation: Graphite does not leave any residue when burnt in air because :- Graphite is completely made up of carbon, and when we burn it in ample amount of oxygen it does not leave any residue behind. Graphite is non flammable but can be burnt only in high temperatures. Graphite needs around 400 degrees to get burnt.It reduces when combined with air. it acts as a reducing agent.`
    },
    {
        question:`#10. Nanometer is an:`,
        options:
        [
'A. Instrument used for measuring micro-distance',
'B. Instrument used for measuring macro-distance',
'C. Unit for measuring micro-distance',
            'D. Unit for measuring macro-distance.',
        ],
        answer:`Answer: C`,
        exp:`Explanation: A nanometer (also "nanometre") is a unit of measurement used to measure length. One nanometer is one billionth of a meter, so nanometers are certainly not used to measure long distances. Instead, they serve to measure extremely small objects, such as atomic structures or transistors found in modern CPUs. A single nanometer is one million times smaller than a millimeter. If you take one thousandth of a millimeter, you have one micrometer,,  or a single micron. If you divide that micron by 1,000, you have a nanometer. Needless to say, a nanometer is extremely small. Since integrated circuits, such as computer processors, contain microscopic components, nanometers are useful for measuring their size. In fact, different eras of processors are defined in nanometers, in which the number defines the distance between transistors and other components within the CPU. The smaller the number, the more transistors that can be placed within the same area, allowing for faster, more efficient processor designs.`
    }
]